VEER S SHRIVASTAV

Head of Engineering | VP Engineering | Senior Engineering Manager



www.veershrivastav.com



Bangalore, India

SUMMARY

With 10+ years of experience in software product development, I have built and managed software products and engineering teams.

My core skills lies in building scalable application architecture, enhancing engineering processes, developer hiring and optimising cloud infrastructure.

KEY SKILLS

Engineering Management



System Design & Architecture



Sprint Planning and Execution



Node.js (with Express)



AWS Management



MongoDB - Design & Maintenance



EDUCATION

B.Tech, Information Technology

Sikkim Manipal University 2009-2013

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript, Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Neo4j, FluentD, AWS, ReactJs, React-Native, PHP, Python, ElasticSearch

WORK EXPERIENCES

VP Engineering, DaMENSCH Apparel Pvt. Ltd.

August 2021 - March 2023

Tech-Stack: Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL, PHP, Redis, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, PHP, ReactJs, React-Native.

Key Responsibilities:

- ☑ Evaluating Build vs Buy
- ☑ Product Discussion & Sprint Estimation, Planning, and Release Management.
- ☑ Architecture Review, Design and Discussions.
- ✓ Actively coding for fix production issues.
- ☑ Team Hiring, and Appraisals

Engineering Manager, Toppr Technologies (now Byju's)

August 2020 – August 2021

Tech-Stack: Node.js, MongoDB, Redis, AWS, ReactJs.

Key Responsibilities:

- ☑ Sprint Estimation, Planning, and Release Management.
- ☑ Architecture Design, Discussions and Code Review.
- ☑ Actively coding for tech backlogs and production issues.

Co-Founder & CTO, Xwards Advertisements

September 2018 – July 2020

Tech-Stack: Node.js, Fleuntd, MongoDB, MySQL, Neo4J, React-Native

Xwards was a mobility advertisement start-up responsible for putting digital screens inside taxis, and running advertisements intelligently based on passenger's playlist.

Major Technical Challenges:

- Managing no-buffering on contents for seamless experience.
- Real-time intelligence for pushing Ads based on logs from device.

Founder & CEO, Tech Talks Certifications

January 2017 – February 2019

Tech-Stack: Node.js, AngularJs, MongoDB, MySQL, Neo4J

Teck Talks Certifications was an Ed-Tech company trying to establish technical certification for Open-Source Technologies. Tech Talks had its own certifications for open source technologies such as NodeJs, MongoDB, AngularJs etc.

Sr. Software Engineer, Justdial Labs

April 2016 – January 2017

Tech-Stack: JavaScript, Fluentd, ElasticSearch

Software Engineer, Pegasystems Worldwide

April 2015 – April 2016

Tech-Stack: Node.js, AngularJs, Pega7

Software Engineer, Tata Consultancy Services

July 2013 - March 2015

Tech-Stack: PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS